JESSICA CLAIRE

resumesample@example

(555) 432-1000.

Montgomery Street, San Francisco, CA 94105

-

• :

A

:: P

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Experienced Snr Technical Manager with strong leadership and relationship-building skills. Have implemented highly efficient and effective Quality Management and Test Systems throughout the supply chain to support a wide range of consumer and professional products. Established an ability to effectively lead, manage and motivate cross functional engineering teams in multiple geographical locations. Am a resultsoriented technical manager who is truly customer focused.

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

Total Quality Management Analytical Skills Engineering Change Control Continuous Process Improveme

Test Strategies First Article Process Overseas Supplier Management LEAN Manufacturing ISO - Quality systems Operations Start-Up Outsourcing Problem Resolution, New Product Introduction Product Life-cycle Managemen Mechanical Manufacturing prod and finishes

EDUCATION

Griffith College

, • – –

B.A. Degree: Business Studies **Business Studies**

Dublin City University

Masters of Science.

Deg: Operations Technology - GPA: Operations Technology

Management Griffith

College , • – –

B.A: Business Studies -GPA: **Business Studies**

C.I.T

, • – –

B.Eng. Dip: Electronic Engineering Ireland -GPA:

Electronic Engineering Ireland

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Hcl Technologies Ltd. - Senior Product Engineering, Mechanical and Quality Assurance Manager Washington Dc, GA, USA • • 06/2008 - Current

Worked collaboratively with Customer Support to reduced the RMA TAT by 30% which improved response time to early life field failures

CM/ODM performance metrics tracked against the product field performance (RTY,

First Time Pass Yields, Return Rates and Confirmed Failure Rates). Improved data entry of field failures, failure analysis and CLCA by 45%

Established the quality strategy to support the consolidation of the Audio and Video Contract Manufacturer, ODM, and Sub-Tier supply base

Have participated and implemented 5S, LEAN and 6 Sigma projects and principles (with \$90k saving on one project)

Responsible for setting aggressive NPI CM Rolled Throughput Yields (RTY) and manage CPI(through the use of DPPMO data, MTBF data etc).

Manage Avid employees in multiple geographical locations (USA, Ireland, China and Thailand), across a variety of engineering disciplines (Quality, Mechanical,

Manufacturing, Process and Test Engineering) Developed Manufacturing Test Strategy to catch infant mortality , early life field failures at the CM instead of in the field

Responsible for Reliability testing of Production released products. Provide Product and Test support for CM's, within Avid WW and Customer

Support/Repair Centers Developed and own the customized piece part First Article

Participate in New Product Introduction programs which included developing the DfS program.

DigiDesign - Senior Quality Assurance and Doc Control Manager City, STATE, USA • 2005 - 06/2008

Managed the QA, Doc Control and Environmental (RoHS/WEEE) team's.

Drove the implementation and standardization of the First Article Inspection Process, Incoming Inspection, Dock to Stock, Supplier Auditing, Color Specifications, 2D $\,$ Mechanical notes and Cosmetic Standards within Digidesign.

Supported New Product Introductions from the design concept to the execution at the CM, ODM and Sub-Tier supply base

Managed the domestic and overseas (EU and Asia) supply base from a quality perspective.

Performed regular supplier audits and managed the on-going performance /process improvement evaluations actions across a variety of commodities (electro-mechanical assemblies, sheet metal, die-cast, extrusion, plastics, PCB's, PCBA's, and power supplies).

Performed supplier surveys / audits on potential new CM's, ODM's and Sub-Tier suppliers in China, Taiwan and Thailand.

Established and managed the Quality Business Review system for capturing and monitoring supplier performance.

Modified the product quality reports to capture early life failures and address customer complaints/ product field failures in a timely manner. Drove aggressive

Improved the quality of NPI's by 55%

Avid Technology - Manufacturing Engineering and Quality Manager

City, STATE, Ireland • • 06/1998 - 11/2004

Responsible for establishment of the Manufacturing Engineering and Quality Departments within Avid's Irish operation.

Made a 70% reduction in the integration and test lead times, by streamlining the manufacturing and test processes -- Improved manufacturing efficiencies and throughput as a result.

Created and defined the Avid supplier survey documentation and global processes Performed the evaluation, selection , on site survey and auditing of local suppliers Implemented Customer Quality Audit plans as part of the Suppliers Test and Inspection process Achieved the New ISO 9001 2000 standard in 2002 Successfully implemented and achieved ISO14001 in 2003

Promoted Quarterly Business review meetings with all key suppliers using the

scorecard method (ratings for Quality; Technology; Service & Support)
Responsible for all the Manufacturing Database design / setup and management - e.g.
Manufacturing test database.; Customer records; Non Conformance; 8D; CAR's;
Program Managed the New Product Introduction, Test and Manufacturing processes
for all products manufactured with the Ireland plant.
Drove continuous process improvement through the analysis of warranty/DOA issues,

Drove continuous process improvement through the analysis of warranty/DOA issues, integration yield data, customer complaints and New Product Introduction.

Sensormatic - Senior Test Engineer

City, STATE, Ireland • • 10/1994 - 06/1998

Developed all the Ireland Manufacturing NPI (New Product Introduction) and sustaining test processes and procedures.

Participated in DFM & DFT programs held in Corporate Headquarters (Florida, USA) Worked on the HALT and HASS programs as part of the NPI process

Initiated FMEA procedures to ensure continuous process improvement and improved production quality Responsible for the technical training , test equipment evaluation and budgeting of new products

Team leader of debug technicians and test engineers

Coordinated with the product engineers in the evaluation, selection and auditing of local suppliers

Designed and implemented the first manufacturing automated shop floor management database

Maintained close working relationship with the design and sustaining engineering groups in the US and Puerto Rico.

Traveled on a regular basis to both countries.

Successfully implemented ISO 9000 and 14000 programs

AFFILIATIONS

SKILLS

Audio, Auditing, Avid, budgeting, Color, commodities, concept, CPI, Customer Support, database, Database design, DFT, documentation, editing, ISO, ISO 9001, Team leader, notes, Mechanical, meetings, 2000, power supplies, Problem solving, process improvement, processes, Quality, Quality Management, QA, reporting, retail, scheme, Sigma, Strategy, supply chain, technical training, test equipment, Video